<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Fosco</title>
    <description>Hi, my name is Daniel and this is my website. Hope you enjoy it.</description>
    <link>http://danielfos.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://danielfos.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 16:27:14 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 16:27:14 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The State of Design Tools: An Unscientific Survey</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Khoi Vinh and the Adobe Team took a bunch of designers for breakfast and asked them about the tools they use. The results, albeit unscientific, still bring terrific insights — such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Prototyping is the Wild West. Every team we met with uses a variety of prototyping tools, whether Pixate, Marvel, InVision, Flinto or others. There seems to be little if any standardization; as new tools emerge and teams find that they offer new advantages, designers readily adopt them and set others aside. There’s a feeling that this space has lots of growth and evolution ahead of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 16:35:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/the-state-of-design-tools-an-unscientific-survey</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/the-state-of-design-tools-an-unscientific-survey</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Designing a good portfolio</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Great advice by Mark Boulton for young designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How can you demonstrate the value of design games, or collaborative moodboard exercises? Or that it took six months of negotiating with dozens of facets of an organisation in order for a content strategy to be adopted? My advice would be to write a story. Show photographs of workshops. Demonstrate how you approach these things. List the methods you’ve used and those that have worked. List those that haven’t and the reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 16:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/designing-a-good-portfolio</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/designing-a-good-portfolio</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I was an undercover Uber driver</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Emily Guendelsberger goes undercover as an Uber driver in Philadelphia to figure out how deep the rabbit hole goes — and comes out of it with a 6000-word article, sprinkled with moments like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passenger&lt;/strong&gt;: So what’s Uber like? I hear you can make a ton of money!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emily&lt;/strong&gt;: Yeah, not really — when they take UberX into a new market like Philly, they start off by paying drivers a lot. So in the beginning, you get a lot of drivers who look like the drivers in Uber ads, like, suits and bottled water and no accents. And everyone gets the idea that Uber drivers have suits and make a ton of money. Then after a while, usually when a competitor comes in — you know Lyft just started up a couple weeks ago, right?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passenger&lt;/strong&gt;: Yeah …
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Emily&lt;/strong&gt;: So then Uber cuts fares down by, like, a lot. Like, here, they just cut fares almost in half. So most of those initial drivers quit and are replaced by people willing to work for the lower amount, who are the same people who used to drive cabs. They’re just doing it for a new boss, for less money and no tips, and they’re carrying most of the liability themselves. But most riders never change that first impression that drivers make a lot of money.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Passenger&lt;/strong&gt;: … Oh, uh, OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 16:19:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/i-was-an-undercover-uber-driver</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/i-was-an-undercover-uber-driver</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>100 Days of Color</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Designer and artist Jaclyn Leneé is on a 100-day stretch doing a color palette everyday based on a different picture. See all of her palettes so far &lt;a href=&quot;http://100daysofcolor.tumblr.com/?ref=danielfosco-linklist&quot;&gt;on her Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~~Update~~&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached out to Jaclyn &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jaclynlenee&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to ask a couple of questions about her inspiration and feelings around the project — see below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your process for coming up with the color palette for each photograph?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jaclyn&lt;/strong&gt;: I’m delighted by color in everyday life. I snap photos of subjects and textures I find beautiful, and pull colors from them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does this project relates to the way you use color in your design work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jaclyn:&lt;/strong&gt; I frequently look online for color inspiration. Since I started this project, I’ve pulled from my own palettes. It is satisfying to design with my own color stories, rather than use a palette from Kuler, or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you expect things to get… repetitive by the 100th day? How do you look for new subjects and/or diff results?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jaclyn:&lt;/strong&gt; I doubt it. Every image is different, the lighting different, the subject different. Endless possibilities. It is all about opening my eyes to the world around me. I take a lot of walks and keep my eyes peeled for color and texture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank Jaclyn for taking the time to answer these questions – great insights for anyone who wants to dive deeper into working with color &lt;i class=&quot;twa twa twa-smiley&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 20:59:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/100-days-of-color</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/100-days-of-color</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning to Love BEM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A primer to start writing CSS with BEM-style syntax by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johan_ronsse&quot;&gt;Johan Ronsse&lt;/a&gt;. Good stuff, although I disagree with Johan when he says BEM is unnecessary for small and personal sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal project or not, writing CSS with BEM makes class-naming much more constrained (and well-documented), pushing you to write styling and markup in a more structured manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never heard of BEM, &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/bem-101/&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by CSS-Tricks is another great way to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 20:46:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/learning-to-love-bem</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/learning-to-love-bem</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>“Slack’s design is not secret sauce”</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I can’t deny that Slack has a nicer aesthetic than HipChat. It does look nice and it is fun to use. But here’s the thing — a lot of nicely designed products never take off or get noticed. Good design is not enough. There are so many pieces to consider and things you have to nail to get a product out ahead of the pack.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Here’s my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great follow-up to &lt;a href=&quot;/notes/slacks-2-8-billion-dollar-secret-sauce&quot;&gt;Andrew Wilkinson’s piece&lt;/a&gt; about Slack and its secret sauce — both have their merits, and both are right to a certain extent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 20:33:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/slack-s-design-is-not-secret-sauce</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/slack-s-design-is-not-secret-sauce</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Asking “who’s the customer?”</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Google gets most of their revenue from putting advertising into the products &amp;amp; services they provide. The people who use Google‘s products and services are not Google’s customers, the advertisers are Google’s customers.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;(…)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Newspapers, magazines, and television networks have dealt with this same issue for decades now. (…) from hiding a magazine‘s table of contents in 20 pages of ads to shrieking online advertising to commercials that are louder than the shows to clunky product placement to trimming scenes from syndicated shows to cram in more commercials. From ABC to Vogue to the New York Times, you’re not the customer and it shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good insights by &lt;a href=&quot;http://kottke.org/&quot;&gt;Kottke&lt;/a&gt; on products and the eternal battle (some) companies wage against their own customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 20:28:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/asking-who-s-the-customer</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/asking-who-s-the-customer</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started with Command-Line Interfaces</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A great little tutorial on getting started with the command-line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of start using Git&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, Grunt or other kind of command-line based tool, this will be super helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Though there are great apps for Git like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sourcetreeapp.com/&quot;&gt;SourceTree&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mac.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github for Mac&lt;/a&gt;, once you learn a few Git commands on the CLI, everyday things become &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; faster.&lt;/small&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 19:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/getting-started-with-command-line-interfaces</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/getting-started-with-command-line-interfaces</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Slack’s $2.8 Billion Dollar Secret Sauce</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Like a well-built home, great software focuses on giving its users hundreds of small, satisfying interactions. A great transition in a mobile app gives us the same feeling we get from using a well-made door handle on a solid oak door — you may not be able to put your finger on it, but man, does the house ever feel well built. Slack is really fun to use. It feels like a well-built house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew Wilkinson lays out the design work they did for Slack and how it is (or might be?) their secret recipe for success.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 09:15:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/slacks-2-8-billion-dollar-secret-sauce</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/slacks-2-8-billion-dollar-secret-sauce</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Foursquare on Apple Watch</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re been working towards this “when you walk around, your phone should buzz you and tell you about the awesome things you don’t yet know about” vision of the future for a long time. Honestly, we were thinking about this stuff with Dodgeball @ Google, and were motivated to build Foursquare because we wanted this to exist so badly. So, want a brief history of how we got from 2009 -&amp;gt; 2015?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buried deep inside a Product Hunt discussion thread, Foursquare founder &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dens&quot;&gt;Dennis Crowley&lt;/a&gt; gives a recap of Foursquare’s design history and lays out the vision behind their Apple Watch app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essential reading for anyone looking to understand the long-term evolution of a product.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 08:59:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/foursquare-on-apple-watch</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/foursquare-on-apple-watch</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
