<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Fosco</title>
    <description>Hi, my name is Daniel and this is my website. Hope you enjoy it.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 20:02:02 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 20:02:02 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nobody Famous</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Anil Dash shares what it’s like to have 500.000 Twitter followers without being an “actual celebrity”, dropping honest (but also hilarious) insights along the way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In all, aside from making people roll their eyes at me, the biggest impact of having this absurdly distended online network is that it makes my online life really weird. The weirdness is probably best demonstrated by a few of the recurring conversations that arise as a result:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Yo, can you listen to my mixtape?”&lt;/strong&gt; This is perhaps the most frequent side effect of having a lot of followers: People think there must be a reason people follow me, and assume I can do something for them as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;(…)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Kill yourself!”&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a lot of followers online, and especially if you have the temerity to do so while being a woman and/or a minority of some sort , you’ll often just face waves of harassment and abuse, regardless of how innocuous your statements are. I’d talk more about this, and what the social networks could do to fix things, but then the GamerGate hordes will just show up and start sending threats again, and ughhhhh who has the time? (…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 09:58:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/nobody-famous</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/nobody-famous</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Marvel vs. InVision — and the race for the prototyping crowd</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing Marvel UX Testing Tools Beta&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We’re introducing some incredible tools that will allow you to get in-depth insights into how users interact with your prototypes including:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Screen recordings of users moving through your prototype&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Indicators of where users tapped or clicked on each screen&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;User reactions via audio and video feedback as they use your prototype&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ability to share test results with your team and stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past 3 years or so, a lot of prototyping tools popped up in the market, with Marvel and InVision being the leaders in the &lt;em&gt;export-your-png-assets-and-link-them-with-hotspots&lt;/em&gt; category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;InVision has been paving the way with an extensive feature-set, being the first to offer Dropbox integration, automatic Sketch import, as well as the only one to add a &lt;em&gt;Google Hangouts&lt;/em&gt; style live-call for remote user testing (it’s absolutely fantastic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marvel, on the other hand, has been on its own feature-spree the past few months: just after releasing prototype annotations and a Sketch import plugin, they now announced this beta for screen &amp;amp; front-camera recording — which, without jumping to early conclusions, seems to be a killer feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only that, but this kind of feature ties in pretty closely to one of the most pressing needs of user testing: hell, if you’re giving me prototyping tools, might as well make it easier to record and evaluate my test results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;InVision, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/invision-2&quot;&gt;$35m in funding&lt;/a&gt; rolling in since early 2012, had a good head start, but Marvel’s &lt;em&gt;mere&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/marvel&quot;&gt;$900k&lt;/a&gt; raised last year is clearly being put to good use by their team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering the gigantic difference in funding they have, Marvel is kicking some serious Invision ass — while also raising the question of “perhaps you shouldn’t take &lt;strong&gt;35 million dollars&lt;/strong&gt; in funding for a freaking prototyping tool?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then again, who am I to say how one should or should not run their company? Although Fred Wilson provides a compelling argument for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yC_tjoQmf5g&quot;&gt;why raising too much capital can be a bad thing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 09:38:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/marvel-vs-invision-and-the-race-for-the-prototyping-crowd</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/marvel-vs-invision-and-the-race-for-the-prototyping-crowd</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Psicodelia and Animations in Google’s Material Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Solid roundup of good (and bad) practices for Material Design animations by my buddy &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RafaTorres&quot;&gt;Rafa Torres&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 10:24:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/psicodelia-and-animations-in-google-material-design</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/psicodelia-and-animations-in-google-material-design</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Facebook isn’t a charity. The poor will pay by surrendering their data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s Evgeny Morozov (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/evgenymorozov&quot;&gt;@evgenymorozov&lt;/a&gt;) destroying Facebook and Google’s ambition to “spread connectivity across the globe” in a single blow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Facebook, Google’s closest competitor, pulls the same trick with connectivity. Its Internet.org initiative, which now operates in Latin America, south-east Asia and Africa, was ostensibly launched to promote digital inclusion and get the poor in the developing world online. Online they do get but it’s a very particular kind of “online”: Facebook and a few other sites and apps are free but users have to pay for everything else, often based on how much data their individual apps consume. As a result, few of these people – remember, we are talking about very poor populations – are likely to afford the world outside Facebook’s content empire.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Here is the Varian rule at work again: on the face of it, the poor do get what the rich have already – internet connectivity. But the key difference is not hard to spot. Unlike the rich, who pay for their connectivity with their cash, the poor pay for it with their data – the data that Facebook would one day monetise in order to justify the entire Internet.org operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google’s chief economist, Hal Varian, has such narrow-minded logic it could make someone think he’s overlooking some “details” in good faith, but when the “details” are the economic reality of 2/3 of the people in the globe, it makes very clear what’s behind the bullshit of his &lt;span class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;“Luxury is already here – it’s just not very evenly distributed”&lt;/span&gt;: a desire to profit on top of people that have much less than you do, providing the same service the western-white-middle-class world already has, for much much more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 08:55:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/facebook-isnt-a-charity-the-poor-will-pay-by-surrendering-their-data</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/facebook-isnt-a-charity-the-poor-will-pay-by-surrendering-their-data</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The numbers don’t lie: Jay-Z’s Tidal music service is already a spectacular flop</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When Tidal made its big media push at the end of March, the core message was clear: while other streaming music services like Spotify and Pandora pay a pittance to artists, Tidal offers musicians a better deal. Unfortunately, Tidal also opted to use super stars like Nicki Minaj and Beyonce as spokespersons for the app. The result was the ultimate mixed message: You should feel sorry about how little money Nicki makes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spot on analysis of why hardly anybody gives a crap about Tidal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kEsJqtiU-2A&quot;&gt;humorous video&lt;/a&gt; also drives the point home pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 08:33:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/the-numbers-dont-lie-jay-z-tidal-music-service-is-already-a-spectacular-flop</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/the-numbers-dont-lie-jay-z-tidal-music-service-is-already-a-spectacular-flop</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning to See</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Learning to design is, first of all, learning to see. Designers see more, and more precisely. This is a blessing and a curse—once we have learned to see design, both good and bad, we cannot un-see. The downside is that the more you learn to see, the more you lose your “common” eye, the eye you design for. […]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is why excellent designers do not just develop a sharper eye. They try to keep their ability to see things as a customer would. You need a design eye to design, and a non-designer eye to feel what you designed.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“See with one eye, feel with the other.” —Paul Klee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great read on the nature of design, from the folks over at IA.net&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 09:50:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/learning-to-see</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/learning-to-see</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Tweeting Child, or What I Learned about Social Media from a Five Year-Old</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;His tweets can be cute, or goofy, or nonsensical, and always, always childish. They show the five year-old’s view of the touchscreen keyboard, the emoji set, the world captured by a phone camera and Google image search. They reveal some of his interests — sharks, himself and his family—and his mode of expression. […]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Emoji are such a perfect medium for a child. […] “I like how beautiful they are,” says @beebaaahp. “Emoji is cool and it has amazing pictures. I like to type emoji a lot and be funny.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 09:40:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/the-tweeting-child-or-what-i-learned-about-social-media-from-a-five-year-old</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/the-tweeting-child-or-what-i-learned-about-social-media-from-a-five-year-old</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hitting the Self-Destruct Button</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently nuked my personal website, partly inspired by Kevin M. Jackson’s &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; site above. This link blog is pretty much what’s left of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without getting too sentimental about it, the weight of keeping a &lt;em&gt;personal brand&lt;/em&gt; while selling myself as a designer and constantly worrying about presenting my old work was beginning to weight on my shoulders. Better to nuke the whole thing and start fresh &lt;sup&gt;&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, if you’re in the midst of re-doing your portfolio, &lt;a href=&quot;http://alexcican.com/post/personal-websites/&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Cican might come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s relevant to note that my personal website is not my main source of work and/or revenue, &lt;em&gt;by any means&lt;/em&gt;. Needless to say, don’t destroy your portfolio site if your bread &amp;amp; butter depends on it. &lt;i class=&quot;twa twa-lg twa-boom&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;twa twa-lg twa-boom&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;twa twa-lg twa-boom&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 09:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/hitting-the-self-destruct-button</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/hitting-the-self-destruct-button</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why can&#39;t you track periods in Apple&#39;s Health app?</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I checked the documentation for HealthKit […] I was disappointed to find out that Apple did not include anything related to menstruation and the reproductive health of roughly half of the world’s population.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In case you’re wondering whether Health is only concerned with a few basics: Apple has predicted the need to input data about blood oxygen saturation, &lt;strong&gt;your daily molybdenum or pathogenic acid intake, cycling distance, number of times fallen and your electrodermal activity&lt;/strong&gt;, but nothing to do with recording information about your menstrual cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 09:20:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/why-cant-you-track-periods-in-apples-health-app</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/why-cant-you-track-periods-in-apples-health-app</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Legion of Real Life Supervillains by Butcher Billy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;These are all incredible, but Zuckerberg Loki takes the cake.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 09:10:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/the-legion-of-real-life-supervillains-by-butcher-billy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/the-legion-of-real-life-supervillains-by-butcher-billy</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
