<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Fosco</title>
    <description>Hi. I&#39;m Daniel Fosco, a freelance designer &amp; developer. I make things for web + mobile.</description>
    <link>http://danielfos.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://danielfos.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 15:30:40 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 15:30:40 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Tiny Designer: How Designers and Non-Designers can get along</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each of us has a tiny designer somewhere inside&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We can all contribute to a design. You probably think that’s ridiculous, but that’s also the reason design projects can devolve so quickly: respect is lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dual email course for designers and non-designers to improve understanding between both parts and make the design process less stressful and more productive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 12:10:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/the-tiny-designer-how-designers%E2%80%93and%E2%80%93non-designers%E2%80%93can-get-along</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/the-tiny-designer-how-designers%E2%80%93and%E2%80%93non-designers%E2%80%93can-get-along</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Women of Silicon Valley — Sophie Xie</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I first found out about this project through their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/womenofsiliconvalley&quot;&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; and was glad when they started doing more in-depth interviews on Medium. The first is with Sophie Xie, product designer formely working on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interview says a lot about being a woman in tech, including things that sometimes go unnoticed for me as a man. If men want to change the subtle sexist behavior in their workspace, paying actual attention to what we’re doing is the first step (I guess).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, as far as advice goes, you can’t really get more badass than this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What advice do you have for any girls pursuing a future in tech?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;tldr; I was successful in moments I quit being a nice girl and started becoming a monster.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 12:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/women-of-silicon-valley-sophie-xie-women-of-silicon-valley-sophie-xie</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/women-of-silicon-valley-sophie-xie-women-of-silicon-valley-sophie-xie</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Modern Design Tools: Using Real Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Another entry in Josh Puckett’s exploration on future design tools for the workflow we need today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I believe one of the biggest flaws of today’s tools is their failure to allow designers to easily work with real data. (…)&lt;br /&gt;
We spend an inordinate amount of time making our pixel-perfect fabrications. We then make sub-optimal decisions based on this, considering only our single, perfect state. We are surprised when our designs are implemented because we forgot to solve a variety of edge cases and problems. When we don’t work with real data, &lt;em&gt;we deceive ourselves&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 11:37:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/modern-design-tools-using-real-data</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/modern-design-tools-using-real-data</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Martian - Official Trailer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YES!!!&lt;/strong&gt; This trailer is just as amazing as it should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t read &lt;a href=&quot;http://smile.amazon.com/Martian-Andy-Weir/dp/0553418025/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1433783615&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=the+martian&amp;amp;pebp=1433783641247&amp;amp;perid=07ENP3N7Z7YRBV5MD92T&amp;amp;sa-no-redirect=1&quot;&gt;the book&lt;/a&gt; yet, now it’s the best time there is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 11:12:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/the-martian-official-trailer</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/the-martian-official-trailer</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building a UX Team</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently came across this past issue from the Mailchimp UX Newsletter and remembered how outstanding is their writing. If you haven’t subscribed yet, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theuxnewsletter.com/&quot;&gt;do it now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some highlights from the issue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hiring&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hiring&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s easy to hire someone who’s mediocre, but it’s really hard to fire them. Mediocre people are a drag on quality and moral, but they tend to do just enough good work to stick around. Managers have a tough time justifying letting them go because there’s no actionable offense. The scent of mediocrity on your team will also scare off talented candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;respect&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Respect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Respect between design and development is the most critical ingredient when making great products. It’s rare that respect between design and development happens organically. It has to be a core value of a company, demonstrated by leadership daily.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Respect fosters a can-do attitude. Ideas are freely shared when they’re valued by colleagues, even when they’re not necessarily a winner. We could do a lot better if we started with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jesterzimprov.com/fundamental-improv-principles/&quot;&gt;“Yes, and..” instead of “No.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;team-size&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team Size&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Our UX team is tiny. Twelve of us do the research, design the UI, and build the front-end of the app. The engineering team we work with is equally small. But our size is not a shortcoming; it’s an advantage. Communication is easy when teams are small. Planning happens quickly so we can get back to making.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Each little team has the autonomy to make decisions about their work, and when there’s uncertainty, they can go discuss with another autonomous team that can provide more definitive direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are traits I hope to find and foster at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vtex.com/&quot;&gt;VTEX&lt;/a&gt;, with whom I just started working as a product designer. The fact that this article about UX was shared by a developer from our team tells me these methods are already under way for the most part &lt;i class=&quot;twa twa-smile&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 08:31:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/building-a-ux-team</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/building-a-ux-team</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rapidly Animate with Keynote</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had heard before how far you can go with animations on Keynote, but this article just smashes the point through your skull — the two videos are super handy for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s no way I’m not trying this for prototyping really soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 08:25:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/rapidly-animate-with-keynote</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/rapidly-animate-with-keynote</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On the topic of impostor syndrome</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Web Developer Ray Bango talks about impostor syndrome and how the ever-increasing pace of web technologies makes us all feel like we’re in a hamster wheel. Make sure to watch the short video embeded in the article, really drives the point home!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 08:20:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/on-the-topic-of-impostor-syndrome</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/on-the-topic-of-impostor-syndrome</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Modern Design Tools</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We live in a world that is dynamic, designing and building software that lives on devices that are always changing and evolving. These devices have multiple screen sizes, densities, orientations. Our experiences live in this medium, and adapt to ever-changing constraints. This leads us to an important principle:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design tools should have the same properties as the medium for which we are designing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josh Puckett does an exploration on the properties of future design tools. Meanwhile, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@almonk/design-like-it-s-1999-48ce5f5be14&quot;&gt;Alasdair Monk&lt;/a&gt; is building something quite like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between Sketch, Framer, Pixate, Affinity Designer and this, I can wait barely wait to see the landscape of design tools in the next 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related:&lt;/strong&gt; Khoi Vinh’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.subtraction.com/2015/06/02/the-subtraction-com-design-tools-survey/&quot;&gt;survey&lt;/a&gt; on the current state of design tools&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 08:04:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/modern-design-tools</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/modern-design-tools</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ZELDMAN.COM is 20 years old</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I started this site with animated gifs and splash pages while living in a cheap rent stabilized apartment. PageSpinner was my jam. I was in love with HTML and certain that the whole world was about to learn it, ushering in a new era of DIY media, free expression, peace and democracy and human rights worldwide. That part didn’t work out so well, although the kids prefer YouTube to TV, so that’s something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey Zeldman’s personal and nostalgic lookback on the 20th anniversary of his website — as much a part of the history of the web as anything can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guy was blogging way, &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; before it was cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 14:40:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/zeldman-dot-com-is-20-years-old</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/zeldman-dot-com-is-20-years-old</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Digital Design, the Optimism and the Pessimism</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An overview of the &lt;strong&gt;plus&lt;/strong&gt;’s and &lt;strong&gt;minus&lt;/strong&gt;’s of the current state of digital design by designer &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/ht_jun&quot;&gt;Hyungtak Jun&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty good points, and the subtle design made just for the post is killer!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 14:15:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/digital-design-the-optimism-and-the-pessimism</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/digital-design-the-optimism-and-the-pessimism</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
