<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Fosco</title>
    <description>Hi, my name is Daniel and this is my website. Hope you enjoy it.</description>
    <link>http://danielfos.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://danielfos.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 18:58:27 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 18:58:27 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>100 Days of Color</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Designer and artist Jaclyn Leneé is on a 100-day stretch doing a color palette everyday based on a different picture. See all of her palettes so far &lt;a href=&quot;http://100daysofcolor.tumblr.com/?ref=danielfosco-linklist&quot;&gt;on her Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;~~Update~~&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached out to Jaclyn &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jaclynlenee&quot;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to ask a couple of questions about her inspiration and feelings around the project — see below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What’s your process for coming up with the color palette for each photograph?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jaclyn&lt;/strong&gt;: I’m delighted by color in everyday life. I snap photos of subjects and textures I find beautiful, and pull colors from them.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does this project relates to the way you use color in your design work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jaclyn:&lt;/strong&gt; I frequently look online for color inspiration. Since I started this project, I’ve pulled from my own palettes. It is satisfying to design with my own color stories, rather than use a palette from Kuler, or elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you expect things to get… repetitive by the 100th day? How do you look for new subjects and/or diff results?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jaclyn:&lt;/strong&gt; I doubt it. Every image is different, the lighting different, the subject different. Endless possibilities. It is all about opening my eyes to the world around me. I take a lot of walks and keep my eyes peeled for color and texture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to thank Jaclyn for taking the time to answer these questions – great insights for anyone who wants to dive deeper into working with color &lt;i class=&quot;twa twa twa-smiley&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 20:59:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/100-days-of-color</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/100-days-of-color</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning to Love BEM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A primer to start writing CSS with BEM-style syntax by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johan_ronsse&quot;&gt;Johan Ronsse&lt;/a&gt;. Good stuff, although I disagree with Johan when he says BEM is unnecessary for small and personal sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal project or not, writing CSS with BEM makes class-naming much more constrained (and well-documented), pushing you to write styling and markup in a more structured manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never heard of BEM, &lt;a href=&quot;https://css-tricks.com/bem-101/&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by CSS-Tricks is another great way to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 20:46:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/learning-to-love-bem</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/learning-to-love-bem</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>“Slack’s design is not secret sauce”</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I can’t deny that Slack has a nicer aesthetic than HipChat. It does look nice and it is fun to use. But here’s the thing — a lot of nicely designed products never take off or get noticed. Good design is not enough. There are so many pieces to consider and things you have to nail to get a product out ahead of the pack.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Here’s my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great follow-up to &lt;a href=&quot;/notes/slacks-2-8-billion-dollar-secret-sauce&quot;&gt;Andrew Wilkinson’s piece&lt;/a&gt; about Slack and its secret sauce — both have their merits, and both are right to a certain extent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 20:33:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/slack-s-design-is-not-secret-sauce</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/slack-s-design-is-not-secret-sauce</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Asking “who’s the customer?”</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Google gets most of their revenue from putting advertising into the products &amp;amp; services they provide. The people who use Google‘s products and services are not Google’s customers, the advertisers are Google’s customers.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;(…)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Newspapers, magazines, and television networks have dealt with this same issue for decades now. (…) from hiding a magazine‘s table of contents in 20 pages of ads to shrieking online advertising to commercials that are louder than the shows to clunky product placement to trimming scenes from syndicated shows to cram in more commercials. From ABC to Vogue to the New York Times, you’re not the customer and it shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good insights by &lt;a href=&quot;http://kottke.org/&quot;&gt;Kottke&lt;/a&gt; on products and the eternal battle (some) companies wage against their own customers.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 20:28:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/asking-who-s-the-customer</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/asking-who-s-the-customer</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started with Command-Line Interfaces</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A great little tutorial on getting started with the command-line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking of start using Git&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, Grunt or other kind of command-line based tool, this will be super helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Though there are great apps for Git like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sourcetreeapp.com/&quot;&gt;SourceTree&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://mac.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github for Mac&lt;/a&gt;, once you learn a few Git commands on the CLI, everyday things become &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; faster.&lt;/small&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 19:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/getting-started-with-command-line-interfaces</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/getting-started-with-command-line-interfaces</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Slack’s $2.8 Billion Dollar Secret Sauce</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Like a well-built home, great software focuses on giving its users hundreds of small, satisfying interactions. A great transition in a mobile app gives us the same feeling we get from using a well-made door handle on a solid oak door — you may not be able to put your finger on it, but man, does the house ever feel well built. Slack is really fun to use. It feels like a well-built house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew Wilkinson lays out the design work they did for Slack and how it is (or might be?) their secret recipe for success.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 09:15:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/slacks-2-8-billion-dollar-secret-sauce</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/slacks-2-8-billion-dollar-secret-sauce</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Foursquare on Apple Watch</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re been working towards this “when you walk around, your phone should buzz you and tell you about the awesome things you don’t yet know about” vision of the future for a long time. Honestly, we were thinking about this stuff with Dodgeball @ Google, and were motivated to build Foursquare because we wanted this to exist so badly. So, want a brief history of how we got from 2009 -&amp;gt; 2015?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buried deep inside a Product Hunt discussion thread, Foursquare founder &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dens&quot;&gt;Dennis Crowley&lt;/a&gt; gives a recap of Foursquare’s design history and lays out the vision behind their Apple Watch app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essential reading for anyone looking to understand the long-term evolution of a product.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 08:59:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/foursquare-on-apple-watch</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/foursquare-on-apple-watch</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>RightFont App</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A tiny Mac app for people tired of the old Fontbook. Still in beta, but pretty useful — allows for filtering by Google or Typekit fonts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get it for free &lt;a href=&quot;http://rightfontapp.com/?ref=danielfosco-linklist&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 08:52:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/rightfont-app</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/rightfont-app</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nobody Famous</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Anil Dash shares what it’s like to have 500.000 Twitter followers without being an “actual celebrity”, dropping honest (but also hilarious) insights along the way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In all, aside from making people roll their eyes at me, the biggest impact of having this absurdly distended online network is that it makes my online life really weird. The weirdness is probably best demonstrated by a few of the recurring conversations that arise as a result:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Yo, can you listen to my mixtape?”&lt;/strong&gt; This is perhaps the most frequent side effect of having a lot of followers: People think there must be a reason people follow me, and assume I can do something for them as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;(…)&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Kill yourself!”&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a lot of followers online, and especially if you have the temerity to do so while being a woman and/or a minority of some sort , you’ll often just face waves of harassment and abuse, regardless of how innocuous your statements are. I’d talk more about this, and what the social networks could do to fix things, but then the GamerGate hordes will just show up and start sending threats again, and ughhhhh who has the time? (…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2015 09:58:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/nobody-famous</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/nobody-famous</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Marvel vs. InVision — and the race for the prototyping crowd</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introducing Marvel UX Testing Tools Beta&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We’re introducing some incredible tools that will allow you to get in-depth insights into how users interact with your prototypes including:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Screen recordings of users moving through your prototype&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Indicators of where users tapped or clicked on each screen&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;User reactions via audio and video feedback as they use your prototype&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ability to share test results with your team and stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past 3 years or so, a lot of prototyping tools popped up in the market, with Marvel and InVision being the leaders in the &lt;em&gt;export-your-png-assets-and-link-them-with-hotspots&lt;/em&gt; category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;InVision has been paving the way with an extensive feature-set, being the first to offer Dropbox integration, automatic Sketch import, as well as the only one to add a &lt;em&gt;Google Hangouts&lt;/em&gt; style live-call for remote user testing (it’s absolutely fantastic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marvel, on the other hand, has been on its own feature-spree the past few months: just after releasing prototype annotations and a Sketch import plugin, they now announced this beta for screen &amp;amp; front-camera recording — which, without jumping to early conclusions, seems to be a killer feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only that, but this kind of feature ties in pretty closely to one of the most pressing needs of user testing: hell, if you’re giving me prototyping tools, might as well make it easier to record and evaluate my test results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;InVision, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/invision-2&quot;&gt;$35m in funding&lt;/a&gt; rolling in since early 2012, had a good head start, but Marvel’s &lt;em&gt;mere&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/marvel&quot;&gt;$900k&lt;/a&gt; raised last year is clearly being put to good use by their team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering the gigantic difference in funding they have, Marvel is kicking some serious Invision ass — while also raising the question of “perhaps you shouldn’t take &lt;strong&gt;35 million dollars&lt;/strong&gt; in funding for a freaking prototyping tool?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then again, who am I to say how one should or should not run their company? Although Fred Wilson provides a compelling argument for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yC_tjoQmf5g&quot;&gt;why raising too much capital can be a bad thing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 09:38:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://danielfos.co/notes/marvel-vs-invision-and-the-race-for-the-prototyping-crowd</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://danielfos.co/notes/marvel-vs-invision-and-the-race-for-the-prototyping-crowd</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
