<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daniel Fosco</title>
    <description>The Link List</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 14:06:45 -0300</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 14:06:45 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Learning to See</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Learning to design is, first of all, learning to see. Designers see more, and more precisely. This is a blessing and a curse—once we have learned to see design, both good and bad, we cannot un-see. The downside is that the more you learn to see, the more you lose your “common” eye, the eye you design for. […]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This is why excellent designers do not just develop a sharper eye. They try to keep their ability to see things as a customer would. You need a design eye to design, and a non-designer eye to feel what you designed.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“See with one eye, feel with the other.” —Paul Klee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 09:50:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/learning-to-see</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/learning-to-see</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Tweeting Child, or What I Learned about Social Media from a Five Year-Old</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;His tweets can be cute, or goofy, or nonsensical, and always, always childish. They show the five year-old’s view of the touchscreen keyboard, the emoji set, the world captured by a phone camera and Google image search. They reveal some of his interests — sharks, himself and his family—and his mode of expression. […]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Emoji are such a perfect medium for a child. […] “I like how beautiful they are,” says @beebaaahp. “Emoji is cool and it has amazing pictures. I like to type emoji a lot and be funny.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 09:40:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/the-tweeting-child-or-what-i-learned-about-social-media-from-a-five-year-old</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/the-tweeting-child-or-what-i-learned-about-social-media-from-a-five-year-old</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hitting the Self-Destruct Button</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently nuked my personal website, partly inspired by Kevin M. Jackson’s &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; site above. This link blog is pretty much what’s left of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without getting too sentimental about it, the weight of keeping a &lt;em&gt;personal brand&lt;/em&gt; while selling myself as a designer and constantly worrying about presenting my old work was beginning to weight on my shoulders. Better to nuke the whole thing and start fresh &lt;sup&gt;&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, if you’re in the midst of re-doing your portfolio, &lt;a href=&quot;http://alexcican.com/post/personal-websites/&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; by Alex Cican might come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s relevant to note that my personal website is not my main source of work and/or revenue, &lt;em&gt;by any means&lt;/em&gt;. Needless to say, don’t destroy your portfolio site if your bread &amp;amp; butter depends on it. &lt;i class=&quot;twa twa-lg twa-boom&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;twa twa-lg twa-boom&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;twa twa-lg twa-boom&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 09:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/hitting-the-self-destruct-button</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/hitting-the-self-destruct-button</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why can&#39;t you track periods in Apple&#39;s Health app?</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I checked the documentation for HealthKit […] I was disappointed to find out that Apple did not include anything related to menstruation and the reproductive health of roughly half of the world’s population.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In case you’re wondering whether Health is only concerned with a few basics: Apple has predicted the need to input data about blood oxygen saturation, &lt;strong&gt;your daily molybdenum or pathogenic acid intake, cycling distance, number of times fallen and your electrodermal activity&lt;/strong&gt;, but nothing to do with recording information about your menstrual cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 09:20:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/why-cant-you-track-periods-in-apples-health-app</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/why-cant-you-track-periods-in-apples-health-app</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Legion of Real Life Supervillains by Butcher Billy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;These are all incredible, but Zuckerberg Loki takes the cake.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 09:10:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/the-legion-of-real-life-supervillains-by-butcher-billy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/the-legion-of-real-life-supervillains-by-butcher-billy</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mobile UI Inspiration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Great places to see what’s going on in mobile app design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://beta.pttrns.com/&quot;&gt;Pttrns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://capptivate.co/&quot;&gt;CAPPTIVATE.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://uigifs.com&quot;&gt;UI Gifs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://androidniceties.tumblr.com&quot;&gt;Android Niceties&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.materialup.com&quot;&gt;Material Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://littlebigdetails.com&quot;&gt;Little Big Details&lt;/a&gt; — Covers much more than app design, but couldn’t leave it out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 09:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/mobile-ui-inspiration</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/mobile-ui-inspiration</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Web&#39;s Grain — Frank Chimero</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you do things for the web, this will be a beautiful and eye-opening read.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 09:40:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/the-webs-grain</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/the-webs-grain</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In other news...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple releases their much expected Watch and… a gold Macbook? Nice.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 09:30:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/in-other-news</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/in-other-news</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Buzzfeed is The Most Important News Organization in the World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I know I’ve been heavy on the &lt;em&gt;Buzzfeed&lt;/em&gt; bandwagon lately, but Ben Thompson’s analysis is too good an opportunity to pass up. Seriously, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/monkbent&quot;&gt;follow this guy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This small tidbit serves as the perfect example to his argument — overheard at a recent New York Times editorial meeting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[…] When the conversation turns to a vivid story from Liberia, where Ebola has overtaken a particular neighborhood in Monrovia, one editor proudly reports that she believes the Times is the only outlet with a reporter on the ground, which makes everyone happy until another editor says, “I think BuzzFeed actually has somebody there.” There is momentary silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 09:20:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/why-buzzfeed-is-the-most-important-news-organization-in-the-world</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/why-buzzfeed-is-the-most-important-news-organization-in-the-world</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Marissa Mayer is turning Yahoo back on its feet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On Yahoo’s 20th birthday, a short history of the fall of the internet giant and how its CEO Marissa Mayer is making it climb the mountain once again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 09:10:00 -0300</pubDate>
        <link>/links/marissa-mayer-is-turning-yahoo-back-on-its-feet</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/links/marissa-mayer-is-turning-yahoo-back-on-its-feet</guid>
        
        
        <category>links</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
